<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gregor Hohl on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gregor Hohl on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 20:38:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghohl30.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Projects</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/pages/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 21:16:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description> Python implementation of the board game Hive q-app: A queue management system. I actually implemented this multiple times, to learn different frameworks: q-app with Django q-app with Vue&amp;#43;Firebase q-app with bubble.io Blog posts: bubble.io Vue&amp;#43;Firebase Travel site and blog: Travel site Blog </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Hivemind</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/hivemind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 16:11:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/hivemind/</guid>
      <description>A while back, my girlfriend and I went on a road trip in her father&amp;rsquo;s camper van. As a board game enthusiast, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist bringing along the highly portable game of Hive to try out. Hive is a fascinating abstract game where players aim to surround their opponent&amp;rsquo;s bee with various insects. Although I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to play it extensively, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious about the ideal opening strategy and whether the game is truly balanced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Development with No-Code: Reimagining Q-App with Bubble.io</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/qapp-bubbleio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 16:38:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/qapp-bubbleio/</guid>
      <description>No-code platforms, such as Bubble.io, have transformed the world of application development, enabling individuals—even those without coding experience—to create solutions to everyday problems with ease. These tools support quick MVP creation and fast iterations for testing new ideas, democratizing innovation. With this in mind, I recently reimplemented my queue management system, q-app.ch, using Bubble.io, and I&amp;rsquo;m eager to share how this no-code platform streamlined the development process and brought q-app to life faster than ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building q-app: A Real-time Queue Management System with Vue.js and Firebase</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/q-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:40:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/q-app/</guid>
      <description>As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been passionate about creating my own applications, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the lookout for exciting projects to learn and grow my skills. My latest project, q-app.ch, is a free, easy-to-use, real-time queue management system that utilizes QR codes to streamline waiting lines at various venues. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into why I decided to pursue this project, the background of previous implementations, and the technical details that went into building q-app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bludenz Trip</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/bludenz-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 17:18:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/bludenz-trip/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I impulsively decided to treat myself with an overnight wellness trip to Austria. The previous weeks had been quite rough, and I had just received another paycheck, so I thought it would be the prefect opportunity to get some fresh air. I did not really build this blog to create another unnecessary travel blog. But since I haven&amp;rsquo;t found the time to post about a more serious topic, this will maybe help me get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web journey so far</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/vueexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 07:44:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/vueexperience/</guid>
      <description>My fascination for building on the web has been going on for a while. Many years ago I build my first project for the web. It was a wordpress travel blog that required very little technical knowledge and mainly served as way to update my family and friends.
From python to the web After diving deeper and deeper into the python world throughout my studies of physics and machine learning, I started to give the web another go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a site with hugo</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/how_to_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 09:48:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/blog/how_to_hugo/</guid>
      <description>I thought the best way to get this blog started would be to let you know how it was created. My goal for this website was to have an extended CV that I could share quickly and to have a place on the web to share my experiences. My fist thought was wordpress. While I have no experience using wordpress I know that it is very widely used and I like that it provides a cheap open-source way to the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cv</title>
      <link>https://ghohl30.github.io/pages/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 17:40:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghohl30.github.io/pages/cv/</guid>
      <description>Education Physics Msc. 2020-2022 ETH Zurich, Switzerland Physics Bsc. 2016-2020 ETH Zurich, Switzerland Semester project at Institute of Micro- and Nanosystems:
Improvement of convergence and computational efficiency of self-consistent charge calculations in carbon nanotube FETs Gymnasium 2007-2015 Europagymnasium, Klagenfurt Matura: 1.0
Projects Data Science/Machine learning projects 2018-present (Python/sklearn/Keras/Tensorflow/pytorch) Over the course of my studies I attended machine learning and data science courses that required project work. In these projects I learned a wide variety of skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
